Aaron Stanley Android Developer

Home Address:

Room 602, Building 22 88 Jin'an Dong Road Pudong Shanghai Contact:

Phone: +86 138 1708 0492
Web: www.aaron-stanley.me
Email: mail@aaron-stanley.me

PROFILE

Nearly ten years of software development experience creating bespoke applications and video games using a range of languages and technologies. Proficient in developing maintainable, object-oriented products to a high commercial standard. Excellent communication skills both with internal and external team members as well as liaising directly with clients to ensure their software needs are met.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Development Experience using the following:

Java, Kotlin, Objective C, C++, C#, Android, iOS, SQL, PHP, JSON

Programs:

Android Studio, xCode, JIRA, Confluence, GIT (Bitbucket, Github), SourceTree, Buddybuild, Bitrise

EMPLOYMENT

June 2016 - Present

Senior Android Developer, The NetCircle, Shanghai, China

Involved in the development of "Koko," a social dating application that is currently targeting the German market. Also in the process of creating Android modules tor our in-house, open source projects

Roles and responsibilities:

- Created a Direct Messaging module using XMPP.
- Refactoring and optimising for better performance while increasing code coverage
- · Creating solutions to complex UI requirements.
- · Worked to introduce Jira and Confluence company-wide.
- Introduced a new working process adding Code Reviews via Pull Requests and suggesting E2E testing solutions.
- Introduced CI and Testing tools such as BuddyBuild, Bitrise and TestFairy.

Feb 2016 - May 2016

Senior Android Developer, Quidco, London, UK

Refactoring and rebranding an existing Android mobile application for release to a new European market while beginning the development of a new white label framework with a focus on clean reusable code with maximum TDD/BDD test coverage using such tools as JUnit, Mockito and Espresso.

June 2013 - Feb 2016

Lead Mobile Developer, AeroFi Ltd, Milton Keynes, UK

Developing native Android and iOS mobile applications for a wireless in-flight entertainment system targeting the commercial and private aviation industries.

Roles and responsibilities:

- Developing and maintaining our core product "MPlayer," which is currently flying onboard with Monarch Airlines
- Integration of 3rd party vendors to client specification and design quidelines (e.g. TripAdvisor, BBC)
- Development of SDK libraries for third-party integrations (Android)
- Integration of encryption algorithms for in-house DRM solution (NDK)
- Server API integration for data acquisition and user activity logging
- Creating user-friendly UI's that support multiple device types
- Agile project management with Jira and Confluence
- Supporting and delegating to junior members of the team
- Prototyping new retail concepts involving Apple Watch.

Dec 2010 - June 2013

Senior Programmer, Command Software Services, Newport Pagnell, UK Developer working on a taxi booking and dispatch system called CabMaster, the role requires the development of multiple generations of the product using Delphi, C# and Java.

Roles and responsibilities

- Developing core Android applications that are used to communicate taxi bookings directly to drivers via 3G/GPRS.
- Creating mobile booking server/client solution to allow customer to book and receive taxi updates in real time via an iPhone/Android application
- Developing the CabMaster product to the specification of our clients, including UI enhancements, account management, HR systems and information reporting systems.

May 2008 - July 2010

Programmer, DR Studios, Milton Keynes, UK

Programming role that includes developing both Gameplay and UI features in C++, daily tasks required working with design and art teams to plan and develop new gameplay features as well as expanding and debugging previously developed systems to include new functionality.

Tasks include

- Implementing user interface objects.
- Creating a number of DirectX tutorials for a distance learning package
- Working with a database of items to create a number of interactive systems
- · Creating script command functionality
- Working on prototype projects and concepts

Sept 2006 - Sept 2007

Programmer, Canalside Studios, Huddersfield, UK

Development roles included programming in C++ and C# to develop gameplay, collision, physics and audio functionality for a number of casual PC (DirectX 9) and Xbox Live Arcade (XNA) projects,

QUALIFICATIONS

BSc (Hons) Computer Games Programming (completed June 2008) University of Huddersfield

Award Received: Upper second with honours (2:1)

Final Year Research Project: A comparison between bounding volume and convex closest point collision detection algorithms. Graded A

BTEC National Diploma in IT Practitioner (Software Development) Milton Keynes College

Grade: Distinction-Distinction-Merit (DDM)

Selected Relevant GCSE Grades (Completed 2002)

Mathematics B
English C
Science Double Award CC

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

I enjoy following the latest technology news within the mobile and gaming industries and enjoy discussing these with my peers; I have a keen interest in football by supporting Chelsea FC and MK Dons, but also enjoy other sports, particularly Golf, for which I played regularly in the UK.